Hi, welcome to session 19,
嗨，欢迎来到第 19 节课，
in this session, we're going to talk about soloing,
在这节课中，我们将讨论 solo ，
many different kinds of aspects of soloing.
许多不同方面的 solo 。
We talk about what makes up a good solo,
我们谈论什么构成了一个好的 solo ，
melody, rhythm, the harmonic structure of it, needs to have balance,
旋律，节奏，它的和声结构需要平衡，
and most of all, you need to say something that's meaningful,
最重要的是，你需要说一些有意义的东西，
what doesn't make a good solo
什么不是一个好的 solo ，
and a lot of traps the guitar players falling into,
很多吉他演奏者会掉入的陷阱，
how to build up your own creativity,
如何建立自己的创造力，
how to start hearing guitar parts
如何开始听到吉他的部分，
and being able to put them out through your fingers,
并能够通过你的手指将它们演奏出来，
we're gonna talk about soloing in various different playing styles
我们将讨论在各种不同的演奏风格中 solo ，
and get you a lot of good practice in doing those.
并让你在做这些事情时有很多好的练习。
In the how music works section,
在音乐是如何工作的部分，
we're going to learn about getting our fingers to play the melodies that we are hearing in our head
我们将学习如何用手指弹奏我们在脑海中听到的旋律，
and choosing the right ideas, taking good melodies
选择正确的想法，选择好的旋律，
and putting them in different playing situations,
将它们放在不同的演奏环境中，
so that we can make the most out of the little that we learn.
这样我们就可以从学到的一点东西中获得最大的收益。
Okay, so let's go ahead and get started.
好的，我们开始吧。
Okay, let's talk about soloing or improvising,
好的，让我们来谈谈 solo 或即兴，
what does improvising mean,
即兴是什么意思，
that means just making up of the top of your head a melody,
这意味着只需在你的脑海中编出一个旋律，
that you can play along with the songs that you're going for,
你就可以随着你想要的歌曲一起演奏，
okay, So you are making it up on the spot,
好的，所以你是当场编造的，
sometimes you can kind of have something pre made up,
有时你可以预先做一些东西，
but most all of this is improvising,
但大多数都是即兴创作，
choosing the right notes to play,
选择正确的音符来演奏，
there are many different ways that you can approach soloing.
有许多不同的方法，你可以接近 solo 。
Okay, first of all, you can get some key bits of information from the key,
好的，首先，你可以从调中获得一些信息，
what, what's the key signature telling you,
调号告诉你什么，
what key are we in,
我们在什么调中，
doesn't matter what the first chord of the song is,
不管这首歌的第一个和弦是什么，
what's that key information,
调信息是什么，
that's what it may or may not go with the first chord of the song,
这就是这首歌的第一个和弦可能会做的，
but that key information is telling you,
但这个调信息告诉你，
what major scale that you're able to solo around in
你可以在什么大调音阶里 solo ，
and get the sounds that you're going for.
得到你想要的声音。
Another way to look at is to use patterns,
另一种方式是使用模式，
like our pentatonic scale patterns, that we learned earlier.
比如我们之前学过的五声音阶模式，
Okay, we can use those somewhat,
好的，我们可以在某种程度上使用这些，
it's a good thing to whip out,
这是一件好事，
but we don't want to just go straight down those patterns,
但我们不想直接沿着这些模式走下去，
that doesn't make a very interesting solo,
这并不是一个非常有趣的 solo ，
we can also be guided by the chord tones
我们也可以通过和弦音音来指导，
used in the progression that you're working on,
你在进程中使用的（和弦音），
that's probably the key way,
这可能是关键的方式，
the chord tones are vital to telling you
和弦音很关键地告诉你，
what notes are safe at any point in time
你在任何时候，什么音符是安全的，
as you're going through these solo ideas,
当你在进行这些独奏想法，
or you can use all of these techniques simultaneously.
或者，你可以同时使用所有这些技术。
Well, let's first talk about what is making up a good solo,
好的，让我们先来谈谈是什么构成了一个好的 solo ，
how come some solos are good,
为什么有些 solo 是好的，
how come other ones just don't sound like they fit right,
为什么其他的听起来就是不合适呢，
there's a couple of key aspects to it,
它有几个关键方面，
first is melody,
首先是旋律，
You want catchy, noteworthy melody,
你想要朗朗上口，值得注意的旋律，
as you're as you're playing it, you want to create something that's memorable,
当你演奏它的时候，你想要创造一些令人难忘的东西，
you want everything to fit together,
你希望所有的东西都能放在一起，所以第一件事就是旋律。第二件事是平衡。
so, first thing is melody, second thing is balance,
所以，第一是旋律，第二是平衡，
you don't want to be playing something up high, something's up low,
你不会演奏有些地方高，有些地方低，
something's fast, something slow
有些地方快，有些地方慢，
and just be jerking all around,
只是到处乱跳，
that creates, creates confusion in the listener
这样会让听众感到困惑，
and doesn't end up being a very melonic solo.
最终也不会是一首悦耳的 solo 。
Third thing is you need to say something,
第三件事是你需要说点什么，
one of my good friends is a guitarist by the name of David Moyes,
我的一个好朋友是一位吉他手，名叫 David Moyes ，
who used to be a guitarist for the group Air Supply back in the 80s,
他曾是 Air Supply 的吉他手，早在 80 年代，
and David was telling me a story
David 给我讲了一个故事，
one time about he's up on stage down in Australia,
一次他在澳大利亚的舞台上，
I believe, in Sydney, where Air Supply is from,
我想，是在悉尼，那里是 Air Supply 成立的地方，
and they're playing
他们在演奏，
and I forget whether it was the manager of the band or the owner of the club or something,
我忘了是乐队经理还是俱乐部老板什么的，
he's back there playing a solo,
他在后面弹奏 solo ，
he's got his eyes closed,
他闭上了眼睛，
and he opens his eyes and there's this guy standing right in front of him saying,
他睁开眼睛，一个人就站在他面前说，
speak to me,
跟我说话，
and he relates that story
他讲述了这个故事，
about not just musically mumbling,
不仅仅是音乐上的喃喃自语，
not just playing whatever pops into your head,
也不仅仅是弹奏你脑海中出现的任何东西，
but by saying something when you play
而是说一些东西，
and when you try and do a solo,
当你试着弹奏一个 solo 时，
it's a little bit like a chef trying to make a good, a good meal,
有点像厨师试图做一顿美味的饭，
you have to get all these aspects just right.
你必须了解所有这些方面。
Now, we've talked about many different things,
现在，我们谈到了很多不同的事情，
we've talked about pentatonic patterns,
我们谈到了五声音阶，
talked about major scales and keys,
谈到了大调音阶和调，
but now we're gonna use all those tools
现在我们将使用所有这些工具
to try and see what makes up a good solo and a good melody.
来尝试看看是什么构成了一个好的 solo 和好的旋律。
Here's some things that guitar players fall into these traps all the time,
这是吉他演奏者总是会掉进这样的陷阱，
when trying to make a solo,
当他们在尝试 solo 时，
and they are, these are the things that don't make a good solo,
这些不是成为好的 solo 的东西，
one is finger patterns,
一种是手指模式，
it's great,
它很好，
all these pentatonic patterns that we've learned
我们学到的所有五声音阶模式，
and we've got them underneath our fingers,
它们都掌握在我们的指尖之下，
that's great for when we're, when we're rehearsing
它很好，当我们在排练的时候，
and trying to learn these
当我们试着学习这些东西，
and get those in our tool belt,
并把它们放在我们的工具带上时，
but when it's time to actually play a solo,
但到了真正演奏 solo 的时候，
you don't want to be playing finger patterns,
你不会想要演奏手指模式，
it just doesn't work to be a very musical solo.
用它做一个音乐性很强的 solo 是不行的。
The second thing that guitar players think makes a good solo is speed,
第二件事，吉他演奏者认为制作好的 solo 是速度，
and that's just a trap that we guitar players fall into,
这只是吉他演奏者会落入的陷阱，
you do not have to play screaming fast
你不必弹奏非常快，
in order to create a good, memorable solo,
为了创造一个好的、令人难忘的 solo ，
that's just not how it's done,
它不是这样做的，
if you listen to the solos on the songs that you're hearing on the radio,
如果你听收音机里听到的歌曲的 solo ，
chances are the guy's not just ripping through fast licks,
很有可能这个家伙不只是快速地片段，
he's saying something with his melody.
他在用他的旋律说些什么。
The third is that, people fall into the trap of thinking it has to be complex,
第三个是，人们陷入认为它一定很复杂的陷阱，
if I want to make a really hip solo,
如果我想做一个真正时髦的 solo ，
I have to make this big, complex things,
我必须做个大的，复杂的事情，
use all these color tones
使用所有这些音色，
and it'll end up being a good solo,
它最终成为一个很好的 solo ，
not necessarily, quite often times, it just ends up being a confusing mess,
不需要，很多时候，它只是一个令人困惑的烂摊子，
because your note have the right amount of balance and melody in what's going on.
因为你的音符在所发生的事情中有适当的平衡和旋律。
Okay, so a lot of what a lot of players say is help,
好的，所以很多演奏者说的都是帮助，
I don't know what to play,
我不知道该弹，
well, here's where the tool bag of all these musical tools,
好的，这是所有音乐工具的工具包，
that we've been trying to cram into you, these last few sessions
我们在前几节课试图给你们的，
are gonna come into play.
现在将发挥作用。
We're going to talk about creativity,
我们要谈的是创造力，
creativity is taking all the tools that we've learned so far and using them to make a solo,
创造力是把我们迄今学到的所有工具都用来做 solo ，
not just putting them out there,
不仅是把它们放在那里，
putting these pentatonic patterns out there and playing that,
把这些五声音阶模式放在那里，然后弹奏出来，
that doesn't make a good solo,
这不是一个好的 solo ，
we have to, we use them to actually create something that's that's memorable,
我们必须，我们用它们来创造一些令人难忘的东西，
okay, just like a poem isn't made up by just choosing random words from the dictionary,
好的，就像一首诗不是从字典里随便选几个词就能写成的，
so a good solo isn't made up of just choosing random patterns and putting them together,
所以一首好的 solo 也不是由随便选几个模式组合而成的，
I heard someone say,
我听到有人说，
and I've always thought this in soloing there are no wrong notes, just poor choices,
我一直认为在 solo 中没有错误的音符，只有糟糕的选择，
and I think that is so true,
我认为这是真的，
there are no wrong notes, just poor choices,
没有错误的音符，只有糟糕的选择，
so let's learn a couple of key concepts
所以，让我们学习几个关键概念，
to choosing right notes when we solo.
让我们在 solo 时选择正确的音符。
Okay, the first is look at your key,
好的，第一个是看你的调，
what key is this song in,
这首歌的调是什么，
now, sometimes it can be a C, a C chord, can be in the key of C,
现在，有时它可能是一个 C 和弦，是 C 调，
as well as in the key of F,
也可以是 F 调，
and also in the key of G,
也可以是 G 调，
so you can't necessarily look at the chords all the time,
所以你不一定要一直看和弦，
you need to gather some information from all these different parts,
你需要从所有这些不同的部分收集一些信息，
and a big one is the key,
而一个大的部分是调，
what key are you looking at.
你在看什么调。
Okay, if the song has one flat in it,
好的，如果这首歌中有一个降调，
chances are you could pretty much noodle around anywhere in F
你很有可能在 F 中的任何地方摇摆，
and you'd be in the right key,
你的音调是正确的，
and look at the key gives us a good framework that we can start building our solo,
看调，给了我们一个框架，当我们开始构建 solo 时，
from what major scale can we use in order to start doing it.
为了开始这样做，我们可以使用什么大调。
Next, we want to look at the chords,
接下来，我们想看看和弦，
now here's a very big key of what to play when you're doing a solo,
现在，这里有一个非常重要的关键，当你做 solo 时，
look at these chords,
看看这些和弦，
if the chords are like a C going to an Am,
如果和弦是从 C 到 Am ，
well, what are the chord tones in each of these chords as they're going by,
那么每个和弦的和弦音是什么，
as long as that C chord is going by,
C 和弦经过，
you know that you can play a C E and a G
你可以演奏 C E G ，
and you are standing on the safest pitches,
而且你是在最安全的音高上，
you can never stand on as a solo,
你永远不能以 solo 的身份出现，
now, playing safe doesn't necessarily make a great solo,
现在，弹奏安全不一定是一个很好的 solo ，
but it's a good place to start
但它是一个很好的起点，
and you know what notes are safe,
你知道什么音符是安全的，
if the next chord is let's say an Am7,
如果下一个和弦是 Am7 ，
well, that has an A C E and a G,
好的，它有 A C E G ，
well, what is common between a C chord and an Am7,
那么 C 和弦和 Am7 之间的共同点是什么，
that C E and G,
C E 和 G ，
so I can just play c through those entire two bars
所以我可以通过这两个小节来弹奏 C ，
and it'll work, and it'll, it'll sound correct,
它会奏效，而且它会听起来很正确，
so look at those chord tones,
看看那些和弦音调，
all those chord [spelling] exercises that were so frustrating,
所有那些令人沮丧的和弦[拼写]练习，
here's where they start coming into play
这是他们开始发挥作用的地方，
to be able to know the chord tones of the chords,
能够知道和弦的和弦音，
that you're trying to solo over the top of.
你试图在它上面 solo 的（音符）。
For example, let's take a look at example number one on these chord tone issues,
例如，让我们来看看关于和弦音的第一个例子，
okay, we go from two bars of Cmaj7 to two bars of an Fmaj7,
好的，我们从两小节的 Cmaj7 到两小节的 Fmaj7 ，
okay, those two chords would be like this,
好的，这两个和弦是这样的，
there's a Cmaj7, then an Fmaj7, would be like this,
一个 Cmaj7 ，然后一个 Fmaj7 ，像这样，
now, the notes, what notes are in a Cmaj7,
现在， Cmaj7 有什么音符，
well, it's a C E G and a B,
好的，它是 C E G B ，
so I know, if I stay on just those four tones through those first two bars,
所以我知道，如果我在前两个小节中保持这四个音调，
I'm not gonna clash with anything,
我就不会与任何东西发生冲突，
I might not make the most beautiful music in the world,
我可能不会做出世界上最美妙的音乐，
but I'm not at least not going to play a wrong note.
但我至少不会演奏错误的音符。
Okay, Fmaj7 what's the framework,
好的， Fmaj7 ，框架是什么，
what are the pillars of of that, we need to be paying attention there,
其中的支柱是什么，我们需要注意的，
F A C and an E,
F A C E ，
so when it's time to change over to that F, what is change,
那么，当转换到 F 的时候，变化是什么，
well, maybe the E is turned to an F,
也许 E 变成了 F ，
maybe the G has turned to an A,
也许 G 变成了 A ，
different things like that.
不同的像这样的东西。
Those are ways little secrets that we can use to make a good solo in what we do.
这些都是我们可以用来做好 solo 的秘密。
Okay, now let's fire up the [band] here
好的，现在让我们启动乐队，
and I'll try and play those chord tones as we're going through them,
我会试着演奏这些和弦音，
so you can hear how the chord tones change,
这样你就可以听到和弦音是如何变化的，
okay, so this is number two in your book,
好的，这是你书中的第二个，
I'm just gonna play the chord tones,
我要弹奏和弦音，
great, okay, now those are just using the chord tones.
好的，这些就是使用和弦音。
Okay, now we're gonna try and go a little bit more of a complex chord progression
好的，现在我们将尝试更复杂的和弦进程，
and we're going to stretch those out a little bit longer
我们将把它们延长一点，
and give you an idea of what other things that we can do with that solo,
让你知道我们可以用这首 solo 做什么其他事情，
so we're gonna make each of those four measures double the length,
所以我们将使四个小节中每个长度变成两倍，
so you can have C for two bars now,
所以现在你有两个小节的 C ，
Am for two bars, Dm7 for two bars and G7 for two bars,
两个小节的 Am ，两个小节的 Dm7 ，两个小节的 G7 ，
okay, so let's hear how that sounds.
好的，让我们听听这听起来怎么样。
Now, wasn't the most exciting melody in the world,
现在不是世界上最激动人心的旋律，
but I stayed real safe, I played those chord tones
但我很安全，我弹奏了这些和弦音，
and that's where it starts,
这就是它的开始，
you don't just wake up one day
你不会有一天醒来，
and suddenly magically able to play a great solo,
突然就能神奇地演奏一首很好的 solo ，
it starts by learning those chord tones.
它从学习那些和弦音开始的。
Okay, now we're gonna, let's do it in a different style,
好的，现在我们要换一种风格，
so I need to think what can I do differently that be more appropriate than that style,
所以我需要思考，我可以做什么不同的事情，比那种风格更合适，
now the next style we're gonna cover is kind of a rock thing,
现在我们要介绍的下一个风格是一种摇滚风格，
so I'm gonna kick on my distortion here,
所以我会在这里打开我的失真，
maybe a little bit of delay,
可能加一点延迟，
maybe crank it down here a little bit, get more of a distorted sound,
可能会在这里稍微调低一点，得到更多失真的声音，
let's try that, same chords,
让我们试试，同样的和弦，
I'm just gonna change up the feel of it a little bit.
我只是想稍微改变一下感觉。
Okay.
好的。
Now, granted, that's not the, the, the most hippest example you'll hear on the radio,
现在，虽然这不是你从收音机里听到的最时髦的例子，
but that's basically the concept,
但这是基本的概念，
I changed to a rock and roll style,
我改变成摇滚乐风格，
I need to get my guitar sounding the way I wanted it to sound,
我需要让我的吉他听起来像我想要的那样，
I started using a lot of bends and things which are very characteristic in in rock playing.
我开始使用很多推弦和在摇滚演奏中非常有特色的东西。
Okay, let's do one more,
好的，让我们再来一次，
you want to be appropriate to the style that you're in
你想要与你所处的风格相适应，
and not just play the same thing over and over again.
而不是一遍又一遍地演奏同样的东西。
Let's do one more,
让我们再来一次，
this one is kind of just a soft rock thing,
这是一种软摇滚的东西，
so I, maybe I'll warm up my sound a little bit,
所以，也许我会稍微[预热]我的声音，
put it on upper, pick up here,
把它放在上面这里，
through a little chords,
通过一些和弦，
let's see what that sounds like.
让我们看看这听起来是什么样的。
Now, there I was pretty much sticking right close to those chord tones,
在那里，我几乎是紧贴着和弦音，
trying to make little melodies around them,
试着围绕着它们创作一些旋律，
but I was sticking pretty close to those chord tones.
但我紧贴那些和弦音。
Okay, remember to say something,
好的，记住，要说些什么，
not just to noodle around in a particular key,
而不是只是在某个特定的调上摇摆，
you want to say something,
你想说点什么，
so let's talk about in our how music works section
让我们在音乐工作原理部分讨论一下，
about hearing melodies and being able to translate them through our fingers,
如何听到旋律并能够通过我们的手指翻译它们，
remember the items that we need to keep track of, when we soloing,
记得当我们 solo 的时候，我们要跟踪的项目，
are we creating a good melody,
我们在创作一首好听的旋律吗，
are we actually saying something,
我们真的在说什么吗，
are we in the right key,
我们的调对吗，
are we using the right chord tones with that,
我们是否使用了正确的和弦音，
when you're playing your patterns,
当你演奏你的模式时，
don't just run through your patterns up and down,
不只是上下贯穿你的模式，
try and make some music with it,
试着用它来创作一些音乐，
vary up the rhythm, vary up the notes that you're playing.
改变节奏，改变你演奏的音符。
Okay, let's talk about creativity for a second,
好的，让我们来讨论一下创造力，
hearing what you want to play,
听听你想演奏什么，
I wish I could say there's a magic pill
我希望我可以说，有一种神奇的药丸，
to where I could give you the secret
可以告诉你这个秘密，
and you could just automatically hear what notes you need to play and be able to play them,
你可以自动听到你需要演奏的音符，并能够演奏它们，
the only way I found that,
我发现唯一方法，
you're able to hear a melody and then be able to play it back is
你能够听到旋律，然后能够重新弹奏它（的方法）是，
just by sheer trial and error,
纯粹的试验和错误，
you just do it a bunch of times,
你做很多次，
and you get better at choosing the right notes,
你就能更好地选择正确的音符，
remember that saying, good solo is made up of good choices,
记住，好的 solo 是由好的选择组成的，
there are no wrong notes, just poor choices,
没有错误的音符，只有糟糕的选择，
that we learn about how to choose better notes,
我们学会如何选择更好的音符，
when we do our solos.
当我们 solo 的时候。
Okay, it all starts with hearing,
好的，一切都从听觉开始，
okay, so we're gonna do a little bit of ear training exercise
好的，我们要做一点耳朵训练练习，
for you to hear some different melodies,
让你听到一些不同的旋律，
I'm gonna play something
我要弹奏一些东西，
and then I want you to play it back to me.
然后我要你把它弹奏出来给我。
I'm going to start just up here at the fifth fret,
我将从从第五品开始，
so see if you can play what I'm playing,
看看你能不能弹我弹的，
one, two, ready go,
1 2 ，准备，开始，
then your time, two, three, four,
然后是你的时间， 2 3 4 ，
again, now your time,
再来一次，现在轮到你了，
go, now your time,
开始，现在轮到你了，
ready again, one, two three,
准备，再来一次， 1 2 3 ，
let's start on a different note,
让我们从另一个音符开始，
one two, ready and you play,
1 2 ，准备，你来弹奏，
one, two, three, let's bend that note,
1 2 3 ，让我们推弦那个音符，
can you play it,
你能弹奏它吗，
again, two, three, four.
再来一次， 2 3 4 。
Ear training is of utmost importance,
耳朵训练是最重要的，
we're only able to buy time here
我们只能在这里争取时间，
just to do a little bit of example of it,
只是为了做一点例子，
but try and pick out melodies on the radio,
但试着在收音机里挑选出旋律，
they have songs that you know,
他们有一些你知道的歌曲，
try and pick them out in your guitar,
试着在你的吉他中把它们挑选出来，
and yes, you'll make a bunch of mistakes at first,
是的，一开始你会犯一大堆错误，
you'll sound stupid,
你会听起来很愚蠢，
a lot of folks, they get all bent out of shape of sounding stupid,
很多人，他们都会把听起来很愚蠢的样子，
when they play a solo.,
当他们 solo 时，
well, you're gonna sound stupid for a while,
你会在一段时间里听起来很愚蠢，
that's just how it is,
事情就是这样的，
so you practice in your bedroom or whatever
所以你可以在你的卧室或其他地方练习，
and you don't get too bent out of shape with how you sound,
这样你就不会对听到的声音有太大的变形，
because you're learning,
因为你在学习，
you're learning how to walk,
你在学习如何走路，
just like a toddler is learning how to walk,
就像一个蹒跚学步的孩子正在学习如何走路一样，
and that's what you're doing with soloing,
这就是你在 solo 时所做的，
so don't get too bad out of shape that you make,
所以不要让你做的太糟糕，
you're trying to go for one note
你试着去取一个音符，
and you hit accidentally hit another one,
但你不小心碰到另一个音符，
that's that was not the note that you were intending,
那不是你想要的音符，
it's all part of learning and growing.
这都是学习和成长的一部分。
Okay, creativity is work, it's hard work,
好的，创造力是工作，这是一项艰苦的工作，
and the good news is that the more you do it, the better you get at it,
好消息是，你做得越多，你就会做得越好，
if you're not hearing anything
如果你什么都听不到，
and you don't know what to play,
也不知道该弹什么，
well, start off with a finger pattern,
那就从手指模式开始，
see if that does give you some ideas as you're going through it,
看看这是否不能给你一些想法，当你通过它时，
but basically it's just a lot of sheer repetition
但基本上这只是很多纯粹的重复
and getting better at choosing the melodies that you want to do.
变得更好地选择你想要做的旋律。
Here's your assignment for this week,
这是本周的作业，
I want you to practice soloing over the Jam tracks exercises for the session 19,
我要你们练习第 19 节课的 Jam track 的 solo 练习，
look at the key, look at the chord tones and the style,
看看音调，看看和弦音和风格，
and try and derive a good recognizable melody from that,
然后试着从中衍生出一个好的可识别的旋律，
remember, it's not about speed, complexity or doing finger patterns,
记住，这不是速度、复杂性或做手指模式，
it's about creating something that says something.
它是关于创造一些能表达一些东西的东西。
Okay, I also want you to practice the ear training exercises with the Jam Along tracks
好的，我还想让你用 Jam Along 歌曲的练习耳朵训练，
to help you train your ear,
以帮助你训练你的耳朵，
a little bit goes a long way in training our ear,
一点点对训练我们的耳朵有很大的帮助，
the mechanics of playing the guitar are pretty straightforward,
弹吉他的技巧非常简单，
it's the knowing what to play, that is the tricky part,
知道该弹奏什么，这是棘手的部分，
some start up high, some down low,
有些开始时很高，有些很低，
start different places on the neck, see what happens,
从琴颈上的不同部位开始，看看会发生什么，
okay, we'll see you next time.
好的，我们下次再见。
Okay, welcome to the workshop time,
好的，欢迎来到 workshop 时间，
let's see if we can put some of these soloing techniques that we've learned about into action,
让我们看看是否能将我们所学到的一些 solo 技巧付诸实践，
so this one is gonna be a lot of listening tracks
所以这一次你要听很多曲子，
and you try and play a melody,
然后试着演奏一段旋律，
I won't play too much,
我不会弹奏太多，
I want you to try and pick out a melody as we go through these.
我想让你试着挑出一个旋律，当我们通过这些。
Okay, remember what makes a good solo,
好的，记得什么才能组成好的 solo ，
melody, balance, say something when you play,
旋律，平衡，说些什么，
not just playing finger patterns,
而不仅仅弹奏手指模式，
speed and complexity don't make a good solo.
速度和复杂程度不能构成一个好的 solo 。
Okay, here we go,
好的，我们开始，
let's try a few,
让我们试几个，
let's start with number two, or actually, no, let's start with number three
让我们从第二个开始，或者，不，让我们从第三个开始，
and you try and solo over these,
然后你试着 solo 这些，
how'd you do on creating a solo,
你在创作 solo 方面做得怎么样，
did you get some ideas from that,
你从中得到了什么想法吗，
we're gonna do that one, one more time,
我们会再做一次，
give you a little bit more opportunity
再给你们一点机会，
to get some chances of playing that,
让你们有机会弹奏这个，
okay, let's do it one more time.
好的，我们再来一次。
Okay, now we're gonna take the same chord progression,
好的，现在我们要用相同的和弦进程，
same exact chord progression, we're gonna put it in a different style,
相同的和弦进程，我们要用不同的风格，
this time is gonna be kind of a more of a rock style,
这一次将是一种更摇滚的风格，
so try and use some bend of some notes,
所以试着对一些音符进行推弦，
okay, it kind of has an eighth note pulse
好的，它有八分音符，
to see if you can maybe do something with that,
看看你能不能用它做点什么，
let's try it.
让我们试一试。
Greet, let's try it one more time,
好的，让我们再试一次，
give you another chance to go through it,
再给你一次机会去经过它，
okay, here we go.
好的，我们开始。
Okay, let's try one more,
好的，让我们再试一次，
this is a soft rock one,
这是一个软摇滚的，
okay, let's try this exercise.
好的，让我们试试这个练习。
Okay, now we're gonna do these exercises one more time,
好的，现在我们再做一次练习，
this time, I'm not gonna play at all,
这一次我根本不会弹奏，
we're just gonna let the tracks run,
我们就让音轨顺其自然，
okay, starting on number three,
好的，从第三个开始，
the Jazz one, that starts in C and Am.
爵士的这个，从 C 和 Am 开始，
Great, okay, let's take a look at the next one, number four.
好的，让我们来看下一个，第四个。
Great, how'd you do,
好的，你做得怎么样，
let's take a look at that next one,
让我们来看看下一个，
this one changes to a little bit of a soft rock style,
这个变得有点软摇滚风格，
so be ready for that.
所以做好准备。
Now there are plenty more exercises in your Jam Along CDs
现在，在你的 Jam Along CD 中有更多的练习，
to give you practice and so on,
可以给你练习，等等，
I would encourage you to go through all of them,
我会鼓励你把它们都做一遍，
different styles, different keys,
不同的风格，不同的调，
give you all the practice that you need.
给你所有需要的练习。
Let me give you some encouragement,
让我给你一些鼓励，
good, soloing takes time and lots of trial and error,
好的 solo 需要时间和大量的试验和错误，
you didn't learn to walk overnight,
你不会在一夜之间学会走路，
and you're not going to learn how to play a solo overnight either,
你也不会在一夜之间学会如何弹奏 solo ，
takes a lot of just doing it over and over and over again
一遍又一遍地做需要很长时间，
till you find out what works,
直到你发现什么是有效的，
it's like begin, it's like you're putting words together to start forming sentences,
就像开始，就像你把单词放在一起开始组成句子，
that's how soloing is,
这就是 solo 的方式，
so don't be discouraged with yourself,
所以，不要对自己灰心丧气，
you're gonna sound bad for a while,
你会在一段时间内听起来很糟糕，
that's kind of how soloing is,
这就是 solo 的方式，
if you let that discourage you,
如果它让你气馁，
then you'll never venture out
那么你就永远不会冒险
and start doing what you need to do,
去做你需要做的事情，
so I'll go ahead and see you next time.
所以我会继续下去，下次再见。